JOSH KILGORE JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

615.473.0190

kilgore.josh@gmail.com

joshkilgore.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Full-Stack Web Development

jQuery

JavaScript

AngularJS GitHub

HTML

I I I IVIL

C#

.NET Framework

MVC/Razor

Test-Driven Development

Git

Licensed Attorney

SOCIAL MEDIA



https://www.linkedin.com/in/josh-kilgore-esg-6946b924/



@jkillz2020



@younglawTN

EDUCATION

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | 2016 - 2017

JURIS DOCTORATE

Nashville School of Law | 2008 - 2012

ABOUT ME

I am a licensed attorney turned coder. I have always been a lover of technology and want to use my newly minted skills in software development to solve new challenges and add immediate value to a company with my professional experience and coding skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

APPRENTICE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | Jan 2016 - Jun 2017

- Intensive full-time software development bootcamp focusing on C#/.Net development fundamentals and problem solving. The final three months of the program being executed in a simulated company environment with SCRUM methodology.
- Daily hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects
- Created single page applications in JavaScript in the Angular framework as well as HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Materialize
- Worked with jQuery for JavaScript libraries
- Leveraged Razor for creating and editing MVC applications
- Deployed applications through Firebase, Heroku and Azure
- Source code/version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with Trello and GitHub Issue Tracking
- Solution Design: whiteboarding and wireframes
- Created RESTful API's with MVC.Net and Web API
- Retrieved and stored database information in Firebase, and SQL;
- Testing with Mog
- Utilized Gulp to automate bundling of modules, JavaScript linting, and compiling Sass
- Leveraged VMware for partitioning Mac and Windows environments to utilize Visual Studio 2015 IDE
- Code reviews in Github of peers' code

ATTORNEY

State of Tennessee, Dept. of Commerce and Insurance, Special Counsel, Counsel On Call | Jan 2013 - Present

 Utilized different software platforms such as Relativity, Catalyst and Axcelerate along with SharePoint to review large e-discovery document requests

PROJECTS

STOKED!

Front-End Capstone | Dec 2016

Deployed here: capstone-stoked.firebaseapp.com

Utilized Angular to build a CRUD app that allows user to login, search Google Places API to search for and save a ski resort to their profile using Firebase backend and get a 4-day weather report via a weather API call.

Users can save and rate their favorite runs which correlate to each resort.

COMIC COLLECTION APP

Back-End Capstone | Jun 2017

In-Development

Using C# with the ASP.NET WebAPI to build a back-end connected to Angular front-end that allows user to login, call Marvel Comics API and obtain/save data about their comic book collection. Comic book valuation is tracked via API call upon each login. Full CRUD functionality.